<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source, Free Culture on Classic</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/open-source-free-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source, Free Culture on Classic</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/open-source-free-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools that I came across recently</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/10/tools-that-i-came-across-recently/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/10/tools-that-i-came-across-recently/</guid>
      <description>httrack When I was randomly scrolling in Reddit, i came across a guy asking about how to backup sites and its content in Data hoarder sub reddit. There is came across this free software tool called httrack which take a backup of all the content in the webpage. I Tried scrapping Prasanna&amp;rsquo;s blog page and the mirror started and scraped the complete file.&#xA;rclone The another tool which i found is rclone from the same r/data hoarders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is actually getting benefited from FOSS</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/10/who-is-actually-getting-benefited-from-foss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/10/who-is-actually-getting-benefited-from-foss/</guid>
      <description>I was questioning myself about Free Software and how it works, now I came to a wider and broader thoughts of conclution and writing my perspective here after surfing into the web&#xA;Question: Linux, being free software, raises the question of who really benefits from it. It seems that the so-called startups or large corporations are the ones truly profiting from this free and open-source software. Somehow its gonna get used by some corporate and the code gets closed which doesn&amp;rsquo;t benefit the society and also doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay back the creator right?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
