<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FOSS on Classic</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/foss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FOSS on Classic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/foss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things to-do for SOTC wiki</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/09/02/things-to-do-for-sotc-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/09/02/things-to-do-for-sotc-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Things to-do Freshers guide to PU locations internship opportunities clubs events yearly health center hostels cells for women safety and harrasments deans evnets archieve library resource gym busses student community festivals nearest phc, hospital Department archieve near campus campus safety farewell, freshers culture pathu thirundhu da</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web directory</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/09/02/web-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/09/02/web-directory/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this list using some somewhat arbitrary constraints, to narrow it down from the maybe 150 blogs I have in my bookmark:&#xA;there are “a lot” of posts, for some arbitrary definition of “a lot” (there are so many blogs I love where the person has only written like 5 posts!)&#xA;the person has posted in the last 2 years (there are so many blogs I love that have mostly stopped posting!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacker - How to</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/25/hacker-how-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/25/hacker-how-to/</guid>
      <description>How precious is our data?? Our data is different from materialistic resource because data is unique and priceless.&#xA;Unlike physical resource, which has fixed value and sums up to a linear growth, our data become invaluable when it combines with one another &amp;hellip;not like a linear approcach with materialistic resource.&#xA;The influence of Free Software foundation europe(FSFE) &amp;amp; Chaos Computing club(CCC) in EU plays a significant role in data protection, digital rights and privacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is actually getting benefited from FOSS</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/10/who-is-actually-getting-benefited-from-foss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/08/10/who-is-actually-getting-benefited-from-foss/</guid>
      <description>I was questioning myself about Free Software and how it works, now I came to a wider and broader thoughts of conclution and writing my perspective here after surfing into the web&#xA;Question: Linux, being free software, raises the question of who really benefits from it. It seems that the so-called startups or large corporations are the ones truly profiting from this FOSS by building their stacks with help of free software and closing the codebase.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I learnt from the collective</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/07/19/things-i-learnt-from-the-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/07/19/things-i-learnt-from-the-collective/</guid>
      <description>As noordine asked me to write a note for myself that what i observed as a secretary, here it goes&#xA;There is a constant need of our mind-share with our poeple and also with the new people. I should make them feel inclusive in every aspect and induce the learning into them. Experience that i got from SOTC to run an effective meeting make a clear agenda for every meeting meeting host should be clear to the point of what need to be discussed maintain &amp;lt;5 attendees in the meeting make them feel included share them the responsibility make sure all ec members are attending when it is a decision making meeting have a peer-review for everyone and share their work done in the collective for the past month(drives and outcomes) Take minutes of meeting in rotation basis with attendees list, agenda, summary, date, time and opinions shared.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
