<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Classic</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Classic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a custom dns server</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/07/03/setting-up-a-custom-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/07/03/setting-up-a-custom-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>Domain name It is an identification string that defines a realm of administrative autonomy, authority, or control within the Internet.&#xA;DNS currently has ~300 million DNS registrations. Both query and reply messages follow the same message format. Both always include Name, Type, Class tuples — Class is usually IN. Names cannot be wildcarded but type and class can&#xA;How do we resolve domain names to IP addresses? Resolves starting from the root and makes it way down the network hierarchy</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I need to maintain a server</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2024/07/03/why-i-need-to-maintain-a-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2024/07/03/why-i-need-to-maintain-a-server/</guid>
      <description>Why I need to have a server on my own just because i like it&#xA;Im really interested in having my own little network of things to maintain and work on but i realized that without any big purpose of the equipment its just going to collect dust.&#xA;Privacy, ditching google, owning my data, fun learning and hobby&#xA;We can run anything we want; it does not have to be limited to just websites; you could use it as a shared password manager, host a Mastodon server, use it as a home assistant, sync between devices and more</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
